Finding aid for the Betty Millard papers SSC.MS.00673
Sophia Smith Collection
- Photographs, circa 1924-2002; 5; 10.88 linear feet
  - Negatives, circa 1954-1966; 8 boxes
    - Roll 65 (Box 46)
    - Roll 67 (Box 46)
    - Roll 68 (Box 46)
    - Roll 69 (Box 46)
    - Roll 70 (Box 46)
    - Roll 71 (Box 46)
    - Roll 72 (Box 46)
    - Roll 74 (Box 46)
    - Roll 75 (Box 46)
    - Roll 76 (Box 46)
    - Roll 77 (Box 46)
    - Roll 78 (Box 46)
    - Roll 79 (Box 46)
    - Roll 80, Negatives and Internegatives (Box 46)
    - Roll 123 (Box 46)
    - Roll 124 (Box 46)
    - Roll 125 (Box 46)
    - Roll 126 (Box 46)
    - Roll 127 (Box 46)
    - Roll 128 (Box 46)
    - Roll 129 (Box 46)
    - Roll 130 (Box 46)
    - Roll 132 (Box 46)
    - Roll 133 (Box 46)
    - Roll 134 (Box 46)
    - Roll 136 (Box 46)
    - Roll 137 (Box 46)
    - Roll 138 (Box 46)
    - Roll 139 (Box 47)
    - Rolls 141-156 (Box 47)
    - Roll 164 (Box 47)
    - Roll 166 (Box 47)
    - Roll 167 (Box 47)
    - Roll 168 (Box 47)
    - Roll 171 (Box 47)
    - Roll 172 (Box 47)
    - Roll 173 (Box 47)
    - Roll 176 (Box 47)
    - Roll 177 (Box 47)
    - Roll 188 (Box 47)
    - Roll 189 (Box 47)
    - Quebec, Roll 191 (Box 47)
    - Roll 193 (Box 47)
    - Roll 194 (Box 47)
    - Roll 198 (Box 47)
    - Roll 202 (Box 47)
    - Roll 204 (Box 47)
    - Roll 205 (Box 47)
    - Roll 206 (Box 47)
    - Roll 208 (Box 47)
    - Roll 209 (Box 47)
    - Roll 210 (Box 47)
    - Roll 211 (Box 47)
    - Eda's Shop, Color, Roll 214 (Box 47)
    - Roll 215 (Box 47)
    - Roll 216 (Box 47)
    - Roll 218 (Box 47)
    - Roll 221 (Box 47)
    - New York City, Roll 222 (Box 47)
    - Roll 224 (Box 47)
    - Roll 226 (Box 47)
    - Roll 227 (Box 47)
    - Roll 229 (Box 47)
    - Roll 230 (Box 47)
    - Roll 232 (Box 47)
    - Roll 233 (Box 47)
    - Roll 234 (Box 47)
    - Roll 242 (Box 47)
    - Roll 245 (Box 47)
    - Roll 246, 1967 (Box 47)
    - Roll 247 (Box 47)
    - Roll 251 (Box 47)
    - Roll 258 (Box 47)
    - Roll 259 (Box 47)
    - Roll 257 (Box 47)
    - Italy and Greece, Roll 360 (Box 47)
    - Italy, Roll 361 (Box 47)
    - Italy, Roll 365 (Box 47)
    - Italy, Roll 385 (Box 47)
    - Roll 389 (Box 47)
  - Slides, circa 1963-1992; 9 boxes
    - Art Box (Box 47)
    - Art Box -- Christmas (Box 47)
    - Betty's Party, 1986 (Box 47)
    - Betty's 80th, 1991 (Box 48)
    - Best Nature, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Buildings, Norway, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Ferns, Chile, 1963-1970 (Box 48)
    - Dandelion, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Farms, Ejido, 1965-1968 (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Trees, 1964-1989 (Box 48)
    - Landscape, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Farm, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Mexican Murals, 1963 (Box 48)
    - Dawn of Mexico, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Prince Edward Island, Saint Peters, 1963 (Box 48)
    - Saint Peters, 1963 (Box 48)
    - Guadalupe, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Guadalupe Surinam, 1963-1992 (Box 48)
    - Cayenne, 1964 (Box 49)
    - Cayenne and British Guyana, 1964 (Box 49)
    - British Guyana, 1964 (Box 49)
    - Roll 135, 1964-1965 (Box 49)
    - Ejido Summer, 1964 (Box 49)
    - Ejido Roll 143, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Roll 144, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Yosemite Roll 145, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Ansel Adams, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Carmel, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Monterey, California, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Aspen, Roll 157, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Aspen, Roll 158, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Colorado, Roll 159, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Colorado and New York, Roll 160, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Roll 161, 1965 (Box 49)
    - Roll 162, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Roll 163, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Roll 165, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Cuernavaca, Roll 169, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Casino de la Selva, Cuernavaca, Roll 170, 1966 (Box 49)
    - Roll 174, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Chapultepec, Roll 175, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Cuernavaca, Roll 178, 1963-1992 (Box 49)
    - Yucatan, Roll 179, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Roll 190, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Quebec, Roll 192, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Quebec, Roll 195, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Glo-Color Nests, Roll 196, 1966 (Box 50)
    - France, Roll 197, 1966 (Box 50)
    - France, Italy, Technicolor, Roll 199, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Italy, Roll 201, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Acropolis and Bucharest, Roll 203, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Rolls 207, 212, 213, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Mexico, Roll 217, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Rolls 219, 280, 299, 1965-1992 (Box 50)
    - Mexico. Roll 220, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Mexico. Roll 223, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Roll 225, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Bellas Artes, Hospital de la Raza, Electricidad; Roll 228, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Roll 231 Expo, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Roll 235 Expo, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Cooperstown, New York, Roll 237, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Roll 239, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Roll 240, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Nature, Roll 241, 1963-1992 (Box 50)
    - Roll 243, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Roll 244, 1967-1968 (Box 50)
    - Glo-Color, Roll 248, 1968 (Box 50)
    - Roll 249, 1968 (Box 50)
    - Roll 250, 1968 (Box 50)
    - Roll 252, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Dandelion, aphids; Roll 253, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Dandelion, chive; Roll 254, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Dandelion, Roll 255, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Roll 256, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Roll 261, 1969 (Box 51)
    - Roll 275, 1970 (Box 51)
    - California, Roll 277, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Roll 278, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Woodstock, Roll 280, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Chile, Roll 282, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Chile, Roll 286, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Chile, Roll 293, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Roll 294, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Chile, Roll 295, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Panama, Roll 296, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Chile, Roll 299, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Peru, Roll 302, 1970 (Box 51)
    - Peru, Roll 303, 1970-1971 (Box 51)
    - Italy, Roll 305, 1971 (Box 51)
    - Venice, Roll 307, 1971 (Box 51)
    - Venice and Paris, Roll 308, 1971 (Box 51)
    - Peace March, Roll 312, 1971 (Box 51)
    - Princeton, Roll 315, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Roll 317, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Charles Street, Roll 321, 1972 (Box 52)
    - Roll 325, 1972 (Box 52)
    - Arizona and New Mexico, Roll 330, 1973 (Box 52)
    - Colorado. Roll 331, 1973 (Box 52)
    - Roll 337, 1974 (Box 52)
    - France, Roll 350, 1975 (Box 52)
    - Blue Ridge, Roll 353, 1975 (Box 52)
    - California, Roll 356, 1975 (Box 52)
    - Crete, Roll 363, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Crete and Italy, Roll 368, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 370, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Roll 372, 1977 (Box 52)
    - Farm, Roll 373, 1977 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 381, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 382, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 384, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 386, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 388, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Venice, Roll 391, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 393, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 400, 1978 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 413, 1979 (Box 52)
    - Italy, Roll 415, 1979 (Box 52)
    - Roll 417, 1979 (Box 53)
    - Italy, Roll 419, 1979 (Box 53)
    - Italy, Roll 422, 1979 (Box 53)
    - Italy, Roll 425, 1979 (Box 53)
    - Roll 429, 1980 (Box 53)
    - Florida, Roll 431, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Roll 434, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Italy, Roll 439, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Italy, Roll 441, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Williamsburg, Virginia; Roll 445, 1982 (Box 53)
    - Virginia, Infrared, Roll 446, 1982 (Box 53)
    - Roll 448, 1982 (Box 53)
    - Roll 449, 1982 (Box 53)
    - France, Roll 452, 1983 (Box 53)
    - Paris, Roll 454, 1983 (Box 53)
    - Seneca, Roll 456, 1983 (Box 53)
    - South Carolina and Georgia, Roll 457, 1984 (Box 53)
    - New Mexico, Roll 458, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Roll 459, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Roll 460, 1984-1985 (Box 53)
    - Pere Lachaise, Paris and Venice; Roll 463, 1985 (Box 53)
    - Venice, Roll 464, 1985 (Box 53)
    - Dutchess City, Roll 465, 1985 (Box 53)
    - Upstate New York, Roll 1985 (Box 53)
    - Ithaca, Roll 467, 1985 (Box 54)
    - Florida, Roll 468, 1986 (Box 54)
    - Roll 469, 1986 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 470, 1987 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 472, 1987 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 473, 1987 (Box 54)
    - Roll 475, 1987 (Box 54)
    - Roll 478, 1987 (Box 54)
    - Roll 480, 1987-1988 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 481, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 483, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Mexico, Roll 484, 1988 (Box 54)
    - New Hampshire, Roll 486, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Roll 488, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Portugal, Roll 492, 1989 (Box 54)
    - Portugal, Roll 493, 1989 (Box 54)
    - Spain, Roll 494, 1989 (Box 54)
    - Portugal, Roll 495, 1989 (Box 54)
    - California, Roll 497, 1989 (Box 54)
    - California, Roll 498, 1989 (Box 54)
    - Roll 500, 1990 (Box 55)
    - Florida, Roll 502, 1991 (Box 55)
    - Farm and Geese, Rol 503, 1991 (Box 55)
    - Adirondacks, Roll 504, 1991 (Box 55)
    - Panama Canal, Roll 506 (Box 55)
    - Honolulu, Roll 507, 1992 (Box 55)
    - Kona Valley, Roll 508, 1992 (Box 55)
    - Expo Ektechione Transparencies (Box 55)
    - Chapultepec, Rolls 120-3 (Box 55)
    - Williamsburg, Virginia, Roll 445 (on reel), 1982 (Box 56)
  - Prints, circa 1924-2000; 12 boxes
    The prints sub-series contains photos documenting Millard's travels to South America, Europe, the USSR, Haiti, and Guyana; her political activities and protests, including the Vietnam anti-war movement, the People's Progressive Party, the March on Washington, Gay Pride and organization meetings; and portraits of colleagues and friends, cats, family and school pictures. This category also includes pictures of art and pottery, landscapes, nature and wildlife, as well as art photography. Additionally, researchers can find pictures of Millard herself, often with Cheddi Jagan. While this category is mostly photographs, it also includes related correspondence, newspaper and magazine clippings, comics, cards, art and posters. Boxes 67-71 (oversized) contains larger prints (many of which are duplicates of other photos in the collection), and mounted and framed photos, as well as photo collages, including some negatives. This category contains many copies of the same photo; researchers can see Millard experimenting with light, size, print and color, as well as Millard's notes and descriptions of some of the photos. For more negatives, see the negatives sub-series, and for slides, see the slides sub-series.
    - Haiti (Box 57)
    - New York, Florence, Rolls 1 and 2, 1961 (Box 57)
    - Rome, Roll 3, 1961 (Box 57)
    - Italy, Rolls 4-7, 1961 (Box 57)
    - New York Siqueros March, Rolls 8-11, 1961 (Box 57)
    - New York, Rolls 19-21, 24, 27, 1962 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 17-18, 1961-1962 (Box 57)
    - Italy, Rolls 4-11 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 21-30 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 31-38 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 39-43 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 44-50 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 54-55 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 56-57 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 58-59 (Box 57)
    - Roll 60 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 62-63, 65 (Box 57)
    - Rolls 67-68 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 69-70 (Box 58)
    - Roll 71 (Box 58)
    - Roll 72 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 74-75 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 76-77 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 80-81 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 82-86 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 87-91 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 92-93 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 95-97 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 99-101 (Box 58)
    - British Guyana, Rolls 102-106 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 107-109 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 110-113 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 114-115 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 116-119 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 120-122 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 123-126 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 127-130 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 134-138, 1964 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 139-142 (Box 58)
    - Rolls 147-154 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 155-164 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 173-215 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 216-257 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 258-281 (Box 59)
    - Chile and Peru, Rolls 283-301, 1970 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 304-342, 1972 (Box 59)
    - Greece, Rolls 354-379 (Box 59)
    - Italy, Rolls 380-421 (Box 59)
    - Rolls 424-440 (Box 60)
    - Rolls 442-510 (Box 60)
    - Photos of Elizabeth Moos and Others, 1951-1993 (Box 60)
    - Florence Zimmerman, Rolls 351-510 (Box 60)
    - School pictures, Other Miscellaneous Photos, Rolls 10 and 322 (Box 60)
    - Buggiano Castello (Italy), Roll 398, 1978 (Box 60)
    - Marie-Claude (Box 60)
    - Hawaii, Roll 519, 1996 (Box 60)
    - Roll 341, 1974-1975 (Box 60)
    - Rolls 435-436, 1981 (Box 60)
    - Roll 511, 1993 (Box 60)
    - Roll 348, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Betty's Farm, 1960 (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous, Roll 351 (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 60)
    - Yann's Photos, 1992 (Box 60)
    - Northstar Fund, 1999 (Box 60)
    - Betty and Cheddi Jagan, 1993 (Box 60)
    - Rolls 412-428 (Box 61)
    - Rolls 438, 440, 442, 457, 458, 462 (Box 61)
    - Rolls 354-359 (Box 61)
    - Rolls 371-379 (Box 61)
    - Roll 451, 1983 (Box 61)
    - Buggiano, Rolls 380-389, 1978 (Box 61)
    - Buggiano,400-406, 1978 (Box 61)
    - Rolls 313-316, 1971-1972 (Box 61)
    - 343-352, 1975 (Box 61)
    - "R & B" (Box 62)
    - Wasp Nest (Box 62)
    - Vacation with Cheddi, Roll 512, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Guyana, Roll 513, 1994 (Box 62)
    - Family, 1933-1975 (Box 62)
    - Travel, Rolls 28-59 (Box 62)
    - Roll 321 (Box 62)
    - Gay Pride, 2000 (Box 62)
    - China and Berlin, 1949-1951 (Box 62)
    - Rolls 409-412 (Box 62)
    - USSR, 1954 (Box 62)
    - College -- University of Chicago, 1930-1935 (Box 63)
    - Camp, 1925-1928 (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous Prints, Posters, Newspaper Clippings (Box 64)
    - British Guyana, 1964 (Box 64)
    - Monkey Tale (Box 64)
    - Vase Photogram (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous and Tree Prints (Box 64)
    - Portrait of Betty (Box 64)
    - House, Framed (Box 64)
    - Kitchen, Framed (Box 64)
    - Portrait of Woman (Box 64)
    - Negatives of Nature, House (Box 64)
    - Darkroom Mural (Box 64)
    - Church Prints (Box 64)
    - Log Cabin, Framed (Box 64)
    - Portrait of Rose Farwell Chatfield-Taylor (Box 64)
    - College Dorm, 1902 (Box 64)
    - Living Room, Framed (Box 64)
    - Dorm Room, Smith College (Box 64)
    - Smith Mandolin Club, 1902 (Box 64)
    - Framed Prints, Commercial Film (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous Prints, Rolls 82-242 (Box 65)
    - Duplicates of Mounted Prints (Box 65)
    - Color Duplicates of Prints (Box 65)
    - Prints of Trees (Box 65)
    - Mounted Prints (Box 66)
    - Posters, Art, Prints (Box 66)
    - Friends and Family, 1961-2002 (Box 63)
    - Farm, Nature (Box 63)
    - Farm, Rolls 51-52 (Box 63)
    - Flowers Print, Black and White (Box 63)
    - Paris Snapshot Album, 1933 (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous Photos, 1924-1964 (Box 63)
    - Prints, Rolls 55-80 (Box 67)
    - Prints, Rolls 3-7 (Box 67)
    - Prints, Rolls 24-50 (Box 67)
    - Prints, Rolls 60, 63, 70 (Box 67)
    - Tree and Farm Negative Prints (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Photo Clippings and Notes (Box 68)
    - Prints, Newspapers (Box 68)
    - Contacts, Roll 120, 1965-1969 (Box 68)
    - Contacts, Roll 45 (Box 68)
    - Prints, Roll 45 (Box 68)
  - Photograms, undated; 1 folders
    - Photograms (Box 69, Folder 1)